crossmark.com 2016-03-16

# Privacy Policy - CROSSMARK

The purpose of this Online Privacy Statement is to inform you about the types of information we gather online about you when you visit crossmark.com (“our Site”), how we may use that information, whether we disclose it to anyone, and the choices you have regarding our use of, and your ability to correct, that information. This Online Privacy Statement may change from time to time, so please check back periodically. This Statement will explain the following regarding the treatment of data collected on our Site:

1\. Sites Covered By This Statement  
This Online Privacy Statement covers the collection and use of data on the crossmark.com web sites in the United States.

2\. What Information We Collect  
The information we collect on our Site generally falls into the following two categories: Personally Identifiable Information and Non-Personally Identifiable Information.

_Personally Identifiable Information:_  
This refers to information that lets us know the specifics of who you are. The Personally Identifiable Information we collect when you use our Site may include your name, mailing address, phone number, and e-mail address. We request Personally Identifiable Information when you correspond with us, fill out any forms, or participate in any surveys. It will be clear when you are on a part of our Site that requires personal information, because we will ask you for it and you will have a choice about how we use that information.

_Non-Personally Identifiable Information:_  
This refers to information that does not by itself identify a specific individual. The non-personally identifiable data we collect when you visit our Site may include the Uniform Resource Locator (“URL”)(1) of the Web site that you came from before visiting our Site, which pages you visit on our Site, which URL you next go to, which browser you used to come to our Site, your Internet Protocol (“IP”)(2) address, and any search terms entered on our Site. This Statement also contains more information about how we use cookies and other technology to collect this data.

3\. Why We Collect Your Information  
Our primary goals in collecting information are to provide customers with exceptional service and to provide all visitors a smooth, efficient, and personalized experience while using our Site. For example, if you request information on our Site, we use your Personally Identifiable Information to provide the requested information. We use Non-Personally Identifiable Information on an aggregated basis to analyze customer behavior to help us understand how visitors use our Site and to measure interest in the various pages. We use this information to improve the content of our Site and to make it easier to use.

4\. How We Use Your Information

We gather and use information in a number of ways, including the following:

_Surfing:_  
We collect certain Non-Personally Identifiable Information when you visit our Site or click on banner ads for crossmark.com services. We collect this information to help run our Site more efficiently, to gather broad demographic information, to monitor the level of activity on our Site, and to evaluate the effectiveness of our advertising. Learn more about how we use cookies and other technology to collect this information.

_Online surveys:_  
We collect Personally Identifiable Information from customers who volunteer to complete surveys, and we use this information to improve our services.

_Newsletters:_  
We collect Personally Identifiable Information when you ask to receive newsletters and other information. We use this information to provide you the information you request.

_Contact information:_  
If you contact us, we may keep a record of your correspondence or comments, including Personally Identifiable Information, in a file specific to you. We use this information to help us provide better service in the event you contact us again.

5\. Sharing Your Information  
We DO NOT sell, trade, or rent to others the Personally Identifiable Information we collect online. Unless we have your permission, we will share the Personally Identifiable Information you provide online only with other crossmark.com entities and/or businesses that provide services to crossmark.com and only for the purposes described above. Where crossmark.com engages third parties to perform services on our behalf, we will require them to observe the intent of this Online Privacy Statement. On some pages we may offer you the opportunity to receive information from companies with products or services that may be of interest to you. If you choose to receive such information, crossmark.com may assist these companies in their marketing activities by forwarding their messages to you, but we will not provide these companies with any of your Personally Identifiable Information. From time to time, we may be required to provide Personally Identifiable Information in response to a court order, subpoena, or government investigation. We also reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we in good faith believe to be unlawful. We may release certain Personally Identifiable Information when we believe that such release is reasonably necessary to enforce or apply our Terms and Conditions or to protect the rights, property, and safety of others and ourselves. Our Site, crossmark.com, or its related entities could merge with or be acquired by another business entity or their respective assets could be acquired. Should such a combination or acquisition occur, you should expect that crossmark.com would share some or all of your Personally Identifiable Information to continue serving you and other users of our Site.

6\. Your Choices  
crossmark.com WILL NOT use or share the Personally Identifiable Information collected on our Site in ways unrelated to the purpose for which you provided the information, including those described above, without providing you a choice whether to permit any such unrelated uses. At the time you provide your information, we will offer you a choice as to whether you want to receive further communications about our services or other marketing messages. If you choose not to receive these communications, we will not use the information you provide for this purpose. If you change your mind and wish not to receive further marketing communications from crossmark.com, let us know by emailing [Corporate Communications](mailto:corporate.communications@crossmark.com) and we will do all we can to honor your request.

7\. Accessing and Changing Your Information  
crossmark.com seeks to ensure that your information and preferences are accurate and complete. If you have created personal profiles online, you may access and change your information by visiting the site where it was submitted. If you change your mind and wish not to receive further marketing communications from crossmark.com, let us know by emailing [Corporate Communications](mailto:corporate.communications@crossmark.com) and we will do all we can to honor your request. All e-mail communications from us, such as newsletters, tell you how to stop receiving them. Please follow these instructions if you no longer wish to receive the e-mail messages.

8\. Use of Cookies On This Site  
A “cookie” is a small data file transferred by a Web site to your computer’s hard drive. We send cookies when you surf our Site, respond to online surveys, or request information. Accepting the cookies used on our Site does not give us access to your Personally Identifiable Information, but we can use the cookies to identify your computer. The aggregate information collected permits us to analyze traffic patterns on our Site. This can enable us over time to provide you with a better experience on our Site by improving the content and making it easier to use. For example, cookies can keep track of what you have selected and allow you to enter your password only once on pages where a logon is required. Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually refuse cookies, or selectively accept certain cookies, by adjusting the preferences in your browser. If you turn off cookies, though, there may be some features of our Site that will not be available to you and some Web pages may not display properly.

9\. Use of Third-Party Media and Research Companies  
crossmark.com does not run third-party ads on our Site. We may use third-party media and research companies to place ads for us on other parties’ Web sites. When users view Web pages where crossmark.com ads appear, our online media and research companies may place cookies on the user’s computer. These cookies allow the companies to recognize the computer when it is used to return to that site. In this way, our online media and research companies may compile information about ads viewed and the general content of the pages where the ads appear. Over time, this information permits these companies to deliver ads that they believe will be of most interest to the user and to minimize the repetition of ads you see. The cookies placed by these companies do not access or collect any Personally Identifiable Information or enable individual users to be identified. The data is collected exclusively for use in crossmark.com’s marketing and research. Our Site does not have access to the cookies that may be placed by the online media and research companies. If you want to prevent these companies from sending and reading cookies on your computer, you will need to visit each company’s Web site and request that you be removed from its system.

10\. Use of Web Beacons On This Site  
Some pages on our Site contain electronic images known as Web beacons, or single-pixel GIFs, placed by our third-party media and research companies. Web beacons, which use cookie technology, permit these companies to compile aggregated statistics for crossmark.com about how visitors use our Site and to gauge the effectiveness of our ads. No Personally Identifiable Information is collected or shared through the Web beacons used on our Site, and the information collected does not permit us to identify users of our Site. The data is collected exclusively for use in crossmark.com’s marketing and research. If you would like to prevent our online media and research companies from collecting this information, you will need to visit each company’s Web site and request that you be removed from its system.

11\. Protecting Your Information  
crossmark.com acknowledges your trust and is committed to protecting the information you provide us. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain accuracy, and ensure proper use of information, we have employed physical, electronic, and managerial processes to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

12\. Links to Other Web Sites  
Parts of our Site may contain links to third-party Web sites for your convenience and information. If you use these links, you will leave the crossmark.com.com Web site. When you access a non-crossmark.com Web site, even one that may contain the crossmark.com logo, please understand that we do not control the content and are not responsible for the privacy practices of that site. We suggest that you carefully review the privacy policies of each site you visit. This Online Privacy Statement does not cover the information practices of those Web sites linked to our Site. These other sites may send their own cookies to users, collect data, or solicit personal information.  
****

13. Changes To This Statement  
If there are changes or additions to the terms of this Online Privacy Statement, we will post those changes here so that you will always know what information we collect online, how we use it, and what choices you have. Please be sure to check this page before proceeding to use our Site. Regardless of any changes we make to our Online Privacy Statement, we will always use your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with the version of the Statement in place at the time you provided your information, unless you give your express consent for us to do otherwise.

14\. Contact Us  
If you have any questions or concerns about crossmark.com’s use of your information or about this Online Privacy Statement, please send an e-mail to [Corporate Communications](mailto:corporate.communications@crossmark.com).

Notes:  
1\. A URL is the global address of documents and other resources on the World Wide Web. For example, [http://www.crossmark.com](http://www.crossmark.com/) is the URL for crossmark.com’s U.S. home page.

2\. An IP address is an identifier for a computer or device on a Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol (“TCP/IP”) network, such as the World Wide Web. Networks use the TCP/IP protocol to route information based on the IP address of the destination. In other words, an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Web, allowing Web servers to locate and identify your computer. Computers require IP addresses in order for users to communicate on the Internet, browse and shop.

Updated: October, 2010
